http://www.maryville.edu/about/privacy-policy/

Maryville University Website Privacy Policy
The website http://www.maryville.edu (the “Site”) is owned and operated by Maryville University of St. Louis (the “University” or “Maryville”). The Site provides information related to the educational services provided by Maryville, its academic programs, financial aid, costs of attendance, alumni directories and events, campus life, and other related information and disclosures; and the Site accepts requests for information, and online applications for admission (the “Services”).
This Privacy Policy is part of the Terms of Use, which constitutes a binding agreement between you and Maryville. Please read carefully through all sections of this Privacy Policy. Your access to and use of the Site is subject to this Privacy Policy and all applicable laws. By accessing and/or otherwise using the Site, or otherwise submitting your contact information to receive more information from us or make a financial contribution through the Site, you agree to Maryville’s use of the non-personal and personal data we collect through your use of the Site as set forth below in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, then you may not use the Site and you should not submit your personal data to the Site. This Privacy Policy may be changed by Maryville from time to time without notice to you, and the governing version will be posted on the Site. Please review this Privacy Policy on a regular basis as your use of the Site will be governed by the then-current Privacy Policy.
Maryville recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of our current and prospective students, employees, alumni, and other users of the Site. However, some uses of such information are required for us to conduct legitimate business by providing information of interest to our current and prospective students, alumni, or other users of the Site.
NOTICE TO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS
Except as expressly identified below, we do not disclose a user’s personal data to any third party. Thus, under California Civil Code Sections 1798.80-1798.84, Owner has no obligation to a California resident to provide further information regarding Owner’s use of the California resident’s personal data. Any inquiries regarding the Terms of Use or, specifically, this Privacy Policy can be directed to the contact identified below.
NOTICE TO UTAH RESIDENTS
Except as expressly identified below, Maryville does not disclose a user’s personal data to any third party.
What this Privacy Policy Covers
This Privacy Policy covers our treatment of non-personally identifiable and Personal Data that Maryville collects when you are on the Site and when you use Services provided on the Site. This Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that we do not own and/or control or to people that we do not employ or manage.
The Site may provide you links to other student and/or faculty portals which provide you access to one or more of: personal academic information, course schedules, course registration, communication functionality between students and faculty, financial aid information, payment information, account status, and other more secure information. These portals require unique user credentials which you have been separately provided. The information stored and accessed through these portals is not governed by this Privacy Policy and is governed by the privacy policies specifically applicable to these portals, which you should have been separately provided. For more information regarding the privacy policies which apply to these user portals, please contact us using the contact information provided below.
Maryville policies related to various forms of consumer or other protected information, and employee or student conduct can be found at https://www.maryville.edu/admissions/financial-aid/consumer-information/.
Information Collected
IP Address. Maryville may log all connections to our web servers. Those log files will include your IP address. An IP address is NOT Personal Data, but general information about your location, connection to the Internet, and your Internet Service Provider. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer the Sites. Additionally, we will use your IP address to track your navigation of the Sites and any internal website searches.
Cookies. “Cookies” are small pieces of information stored in User’s browser that give the User a unique identification. The Site uses only Cookies that [(1) create a user session ID, (2) counts the visits by one user, (3) recognize and collect user login information, (4) log user UNIX computer time, and (5) track views of every piece of content of the Site. All cookies are established on a per session basis, and are not permanently stored on your machine. For more information about cookies, please visit www.AboutCookies.org.
Clear Gifs. We may also employ software technology called clear gifs (also known as web beacons) that help us better manage content on our Sites by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of users. Clear gifs and cookies are not tied to the user’s personally identifiable information.
Personal Data. We may collect personal data from our users when providing certain Services. Depending upon what you are requesting, the collected Personal Data may include, for example, your name, birth date, social security number, e-mail address, physical address, phone number, your criminal history, citizenship, or previous education history with Maryville or other schools.
Maryville collects Personal Data only when there is a legitimate need to do so. Except as provided herein, we will not distribute your personal data outside of Maryville and our affiliates.
Information Use
How Your Non-Personally Identifiable Information May Be Used.
To customize the advertising and content you see on our pages or other websites;
To improve the performance or layout of our website;
To develop new services and ideas; and
To better administer and troubleshoot our systems.
How your Personal Data May be Used.
To provide you the Services on the Site;
To evaluate and improve the Services;
To fulfill your requests for information; and
To contact you about Maryville services and those of our affiliates, based on the preferences you have indicated.
We will give you the opportunity to “opt out” of receiving any unsolicited information from us or to limit the unsolicited information you receive from us to information regarding the Services or information you specifically request or information we determine you may find useful as a result of your use of the Site.
Information Sharing and Disclosure
In general, Maryville will not share your Personal Data with any other person or company. However, we will share Personal Data about you to other companies or people when:
We need to share your information to provide the service you have requested;
We need to send the information to companies who work on behalf of Maryville to provide a service to you (unless we tell you differently, these companies do not have any right to use the Personal Data we provide to them beyond what is necessary to assist us);
We need to send the information to financial institution, a state or federal education agency, including financial aid providers and/or education regulators or accreditation agencies;
We find that your actions on the Site violate the Terms of Use, any of our usage guidelines for specific services or any agreement; and
As required to respond to or initiate subpoenas, court orders, or legal process.
In the event you voluntarily share personal or sensitive information on a message board, comments section, or in a chat room offered by the Site, please be advised that such information may be collected and used by the other users of the Site who have access to such message boards, comment sections and chat rooms. Maryville shall have no liability resulting from the misuse of information you voluntarily share during your use of the Site. Maryville shall have no obligation to police the message boards, comment sections and chat rooms, but has the ability to remove such information at any time in its sole discretion.
Ability to Review and Edit Your Information
You may review and approve the information about you that was stored in our database and obtained through your use of the Site. Upon your written request, we will remove that information from our database or change or correct personal data that you state is erroneous within applicable regulatory or other legal requirements. You should understand, however, that information about you in Maryville’s database might come from a number of sources.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act
Maryville complies with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act, commonly referred to as FERPA. For information regarding FERPA please visit https://www.maryville.edu/ssc/ferpa-4/ .
Change of Control
We may sell or buy other businesses or entities. In such event, we may transfer or assign the information we have collected as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. In such transactions, your personal data may be included in the transferred business assets.
CAN-SPAM Compliance
Maryville is committed to be compliant with all Federal regulations, including the Federal CAN-SPAM Act of 2003. Owner only sends email to those of our visitors who have requested to receive these communications. You may “opt-out” of any communication from Owner at any time, and we will remove you from our mailing list. In addition, you may contact us at the address below and request to be removed from our mailing list.
Commitment to Children’s Privacy
In compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, 15 U.S.C., §§ 6501-06 and 16 C.F.R., §§ 312.1-312.12, our Site do not permit children under 13 years of age to become users, and we do not collect information from children. By using our Site, you represent that you are 13 years of age or older.
Security
We will maintain commercially reasonable safeguards to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of your Personal Data. However, you acknowledge that no electronic storage method or data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.
Changes to this Privacy Policy
We reserve the right to change, modify, or otherwise update this Policy at any time. These changes or updates will be effective immediately. We may provide you notice of such changes when they are material, such notice may be given by posting on this Site, by electronic or conventional mail, or by any other means by which you obtain notice of the changes or updates.
Policies of Other Sites
The Site may contain links to third-party websites not owned or controlled by Maryville. Maryville is not responsible for the privacy policies of any third-party websites which user may access through a third-party link. Further, these third-party websites may have privacy policies that differ from this Privacy Policy. Maryville disclaims all responsibility for the privacy practices of such other third-party sites. You should read the privacy policies of each site you visit to determine what information that site may be collecting about you and how they intend to use such information.
Questions
If you have any questions about Maryville, the Site, the Services, the Terms of Use or the Privacy Policy, you may contact us at:
Maryville University
650 Maryville University Drive
St. Louis, MO 63141
314-529-9300
(Date of Last Revision: May 1, 2016)
©2020 Maryville University | Accessibility Statement | Privacy Policy | 1-800-627-9855
